What if everything you were forced to keep inside was suddenly set free?
Hulk is a science fiction, adventure, action film directed by Ang Lee.
Bruce Banner, a genetics researcher with a tragic past, suffers massive radiation exposure in his
laboratory that causes him to transform into a raging green monster when he gets angry.
Bruce Banner, played by Eric Bana.
Betty Ross, played by Jennifer Connelly.
Ross, played by Sam Elliott.
Talbot, played by Josh Lucas.
Father, played by Nick Nolte.
Young David Banner, played by Paul Kersey.
Hulk (also known as The Hulk) is a 2003 American superhero film based on the
Marvel Comics character created by Stan Lee and Jack Kirby.
The film was directed by Ang Lee and written by John
Turman, James Schamus, and Michael France.
Eric Bana stars as Bruce Banner and Hulk, alongside Jennifer
Connelly, Sam Elliott, Josh Lucas, and Nick Nolte.
The film explores Bruce Banner's origins.
After a lab accident involving gamma radiation, he transforms into a giant green-skinned humanoid
with superhuman strength known as the Hulk whenever stressed or emotionally provoked.
The United States military pursues him, and he clashes with his
biological father, who has dark plans for his son.
Development started in 1990.
At one time, Joe Johnston and then Jonathan Hensleigh were to direct.
Hensleigh, John Turman, Michael France, Zak Penn, J.
Abrams, Michael Tolkin, David Hayter, and Scott Alexander & Larry Karaszewski
wrote more scripts before Ang Lee and James Schamus's involvement.
The project was filmed primarily in California from March to
August 2002, mainly in the San Francisco Bay Area.
Hulk was released by Universal Pictures on June 20, 2003.
The film grossed $245.4 million worldwide and received mixed reviews upon release, with reviewers
praising the cast's performances and Lee's directing but criticising the slow pace and length.
It has since received retrospective praise for its departure
from conventional comic book film tropes.
Reception has been reviewed more positively in retrospect and the film has gained a
significant cult following in the years since its initial release.
A planned sequel, which would have been released in May 2005, was repurposed as a reboot titled The
Incredible Hulk and released on June 13, 2008, as the second film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe.
The film explores themes of california, monster,
general, mutation, san francisco, california.
The tone is thought_provoking.